*music*
well good morning church you guys sound great this morning how are we feeling awesome well if we haven't had the privilege of meeting yet my name is Ryan and I have the privilege of being one of the pastors here and this month has some of you know we
relaunched a nine part series that we're doing spread out over three years in partnership with the ministry called practicing the way and the goal of that is that those of us who consider ourselves followers of Jesus would intentionally find ways to build
some aspect of these nine rhythms these nine practices that we draw out from the life and teachings of find ways to incorporate them into the rhythms of our life so that the Holy Spirit might use them to bring us into the likeness of the image of Jesus.
um these practices work together to help us build a holistic spiritual formation routine it's funny um Jason was just giving me a hard time for how weak it looked I was pulling that heavy uh podium up and he said stop running start lifting because he knows.
that in my in my in my physical fitness routine I prioritize cardio over over strength training and and spiritual formation is similar to physical um fitness in the in the reality that in order to be a holistic healthy well balanced physical person it requires cardio flexibility resistance whole body resistance not just upper body resistance which again is another temptation of mine.
Like what's the point of running hills if you still have to lift legs later in the day so anyway it takes all of this plus a balanced diet right there's so much that goes into being a healthy physical human being.
And the reality is the same is true of our spiritual lives but but much of the American church has kind of shrunk down spiritual fitness to like attending a hour and 15 minute service once every two and a half Sundays.
And maybe going through a Bible reading plan that we get like 80% done and then give up and maybe if we remember to pray for our friends who are sick then we're like we're cruising we're crushing it right.
Anybody else feel like that.
Okay.
Good.
That's good.
Because the series the whole idea behind this series is that we would think about holistic spiritual formation from fasting to solitude to prayer to community to service to all of these things build on each other and we should build a routine that works for us that the Holy Spirit can use to conform us to the image of Jesus.
Does that work?
Yeah.
Cool.
Thank you.
The specific practice we're focused on for this four weeks is on community about building an intimate spiritual community around a table that becomes like family where we love each other and sacrificially serve and encourage and do everything the Hebrews passage that you guys got so hyped about said centered on Jesus where we can be fully known and fully loved.
It's aimed at getting out of rows and into circles at prioritizing real relationships aimed at obedience to Jesus.
Does any of this language sound familiar?
Good.
Because the reality is large group gatherings of Christians are great.
This is great.
It's great for individual inspiration and community impact.
One of my favorite pastors Tim Keller had a line where he said every city needs one or two megachurches because there's something about the gathering of such a large group of people.
You can pool resources.
You can do things that inspire the community.
You can have more kingdom impact.
He said everybody needs one or two of those.
But that shouldn't be the norm in the church experience.
We need to get into smaller circles.
We need to see each other face to face.
We need embodied relationships around a table that God can use to push his kingdom forward to shine a light in the darkness.
It's one thing to have one big central location that shines a light to the community.
But what if each one of our tables was a lantern to the community around our neighborhoods?
The light of the kingdom of God spreads far more significantly in that way.
And it's far harder to see and to tell because all we're in charge of is our one little lantern.
And so it seems insignificant and small, but if you were able to zoom out and look at the map on the screen of all of God's people in our communities, if we took this seriously, if we took our table seriously, our community seriously, that light would spread far greater than it could ever spread from a few centralized locations.
So, that's recap for why we're doing this whole thing.
Hopefully it makes sense.
Let's pray and then we'll get more specific into what this week's all about.
Father in heaven, we thank you.
God, you, we need you.
I need you.
Left to my own devices, I am weak and selfish.
And I will hide my light under a bushel.
God, by the power of your spirit, may we be people that, without shame or guilt, shine your light forward for your glory, for our good and for the good of our neighbors.
It's in Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.
We're going to land in Mark chapter 14, so if you have a Bible and you'd like to follow along, we'll get there in just a few minutes.
Mark chapter 14.
In 2018, the UK created a brand new cabinet position, not for education or for transportation, but for loneliness.
This might seem silly to a lot of us might sound woke to some of us, but not when 9 million of your citizens admit to always or often feeling lonely.
And especially since neurologists say that loneliness has the same impact on morality as smoking 15 cigarettes a day.
And this isn't just a European problem.
52% of Americans report regularly feeling lonely.
58% of American millennials, that's me, say that sometimes or always we feel that no one knows us well.
In the same study, one in four said that they don't have a single confidant that they can rely on or turn to.
One in four American millennials say they don't have one person that knows them or that can care for them when they are faced with the difficulty of something overwhelming in their lives.
We have thousands of followers, but no close friends.
We've confused connectivity with community and our spiritual and mental health is keeping the score.
We're connected.
We move at such a fast pace that we never really allow the reality of our loneliness to sink in.
But when the head hits the pillow, we realize that we're running a race that we cannot keep up with on our own.
And the invitation to Jesus is to slow down, is to get around the table with embodied relationships, to put the glowing rectangle down for a second, and to look your brother or your sister in Christ in the eye.
Is it possible that a major contributing factor to all of this stuff that we have going on in our lives is because we live such a hurried and distracted life and we've forsaken the table.
The table is the central place in both the Scriptures and in history where communities were formed and where individuals built a deep sense of belonging, but we've forsaken it.
There's some studies out there that say that a larger percentage of people eat meals in their vehicles than they do anywhere else.
And families that prioritize eating meals around the table do so for less than 20 minutes a day.
We move so fast, so quickly from one thing to the next that we miss out on investing in the people that God has called us to.
And the example and the invitation of Jesus is to live an intentional, unhurried life where we can be present to God, ourselves, and to one another.
To become a people of love.
And I would argue that the Christian community formed around the table is the place where all of these three things collide.
Being present to God, to ourselves, and to one another happen when we live in relationship and community with one another.
I love how John Mark Comer puts it.
He says, "The goal of Christian community isn't just to know and love God."
If I stopped there, you would think, "What?"
It isn't just to know and love God, it's also to know and to love and to be known and to be loved by each other, to become a people of love.
The spiritual invitation, the relationship with God isn't just love the Lord your God with all of your heart, soul, mind, and strength.
It's love the Lord your God with all of your heart, soul, mind, and strength, and love your neighbor as yourself.
The Christian faith, the invitation to follow Jesus, isn't an individual practice, it's a communal one.
And the table is a place where we can slow down and be honest with ourselves about what's going on in our own lives.
Both the highs and the lows, the joys and the sorrows.
And this has to be something that we intentionally create, just like physical fitness will not accidentally happen.
Some of you are like, "Well, I've been waiting for it to accidentally happen."
It won't accidentally happen in spiritual, deep spiritual formation in community with brothers and sisters in Christ will not accidentally happen.
I love how this pastor puts it, Ian Simpkins.
He says, "If we don't intentionally practice the ways of Jesus, we will unintentionally practice the ways of this world."
And in our passage today, we're going to see Jesus bringing the full range of his emotions, the Son of God, right?
Fully human, fully divine.
We're going to see him bring the full range of his emotions, both joy and sorrow, to the table with his community.
He's going to invite his community into his happiness, his joy, and his sorrow.
The invitation for us is to find a group of people where we can be vulnerable about both the good and the bad in our lives.
Where we can celebrate with one another.
And we can suffer with one another.
All of us who have gone through deep, tragic suffering know that if you did it alone, it was probably unbearable.
The Apostle Paul will pick up on Christ's example in his invitation in his epistle to the Romans where he says to the early church that their call is to rejoice with those who rejoice and to weep with those who weep.
If we want to intentionally form Christian community that carries us throughout the difficulties of life and pushes forward the kingdom of God in a world marred by sin, we have to get intentional to move past shallow conversations and spiritual platitudes.
Come on, man.
And I don't know how many church people you've hung out with recently, but we are really good at shallow conversations and spiritual platitudes.
We could formulate the greatest small group ministry that's ever been assembled under the walls of a church.
We could have enough small groups for every single person and any friend that they would want to come.
They could be staffed with the godliest, most mature individuals.
And if all we ever did was talk about nothing, the kingdom of God would not advance and we would not be spiritually formed.
The invitation to the Christian table isn't just to get around in huddles and circles with other people that share the same ideology as you.
We have to move past shallow conversations and spiritual platitudes.
I've been a part of some groups that had some deep theological conversations, but that was it.
It wasn't how does this deep theological conversation change the way I live with my coworkers tomorrow.
It was just, oh, cool.
This is this awesome piece of information.
Let me parse this Hebrew word for you and tell you what I learned in my whatever it might be.
It's like, okay, that's great.
I love that.
But what does that do about how you treat your wife and you engage with your neighbor tomorrow?
This is what we're invited to around the table of Jesus.
So Mark chapter 14, Jesus brings his highs and his lows to his community.
Let's read it.
Mark chapter 14.
That was the longest intro I've ever had.
Hopefully I can get quicker as we go along.
Mark 14, verse 22.
We could even start at verse 18 and then skip.
We don't have time to cover everything.
Verse 18.
While they were reclining at the table eating, he said,
Truly one of you will betray me.
Whoops.
One who is eating with me.
They were saddened and one of them said, surely it is not me.
It is one of the 12, he replied.
One who dips the bread into the bowl.
The Son of Man will go just as it is written about him.
But woe to that man who betrays the Son of Man.
It should be better for him if he had not been born.
Now, it gets better.
I promise.
Verse 22.
While they were eating, Jesus took bread.
And when he had it, he gave thanks and he broke it and he gave it to his disciples saying,
Take, this is my body.
Then he took a cup.
And when he had given thanks, he gave it to them and they all drank from it.
This is my blood of the covenant, which was poured out for many.
He said to them, truly, I tell you, I will not drink again from the fruit of the vine until that day when I drink in the new kingdom, drink it anew in the kingdom of God.
When they had sung a hymn, they went out to the Mount of Olives.
It's a familiar passage for a lot of us who have spent any time in the church because it's Christ's institution of what we now call the Lord's Supper.
But what I want to hone in on this morning is that on the eve of his crucifixion, while he is preparing his disciples that one of the closest of his followers was going to betray him.
He sets aside time to recline around the table with his disciples and share a Passover meal.
The Passover meal was instituted to be a memorial celebration of God's deliverance of Israel out of slavery into Egypt and towards the promised land.
If there was ever a time for Jesus to sit under the weight and grief of the reality of sin in the world, it was now.
And he chose defiant joy in the midst of this.
He invited his community around a table to celebrate a festival to look back at what God has done in the past to remind themselves that God has been faithful.
Joy is not something that always comes naturally or easy for us in our broken world.
We won't just stumble into joy.
We have to be defiant to look for ways in which we see God at work all around us.
And we have to bring our community around the table and celebrate because if not, we will be weighed down by the reality of life in this broken world.
If the past two weeks didn't, if you didn't experience that, that if you don't, if you just allow yourself to get sucked into the vortex of this world, the brokenness, the pain, the difficulty of this world, you will not find any joy.
That's why we need Christian community to remind ourselves to look for the places in which God is doing something good.
I'm old enough to remember that when you turned on the local news, there would be like fun stories about cool things happening in the community.
Not just like murder, death, car wreck, explosion, and war.
It's like we need to look for ways to see the joy that's happening all around us, to see the way that God's kingdom is breaking in the midst of the brokenness of this world.
This does not mean we don't pretend that the brokenness isn't happening.
We don't turn our eyes to it, this is spiritual platitudes, right?
God is good all the time.
God is good.
No, we wrestle with the reality of the brokenness of this world, but we choose defiant joy in our community.
We remind ourselves of what God is up to in the midst of our brokenness.
Like I said, joy is something hard to come by.
I read a study that said, "Neuroscientists say our brains have a 14:1 ratio for negative thoughts."
14:1.
It's putting us at a bit of a negative situation.
And they said that our average thoughts are 80% negative and 95% repetitive.
So we get this mass amount of negative thoughts flooding into our head, into our minds.
I don't know when the study was, but if it was before social media, maybe 95% negative and 99% repetitive, right?
We fixate on the negative and forget to think about the positive and the invitation that Jesus gives his disciples.
It's to choose defiant joy in the midst of our broken world.
He says this to his disciples in John 15.
He says, "I have told you this so that my joy may be in you and that your joy may be complete."
Jesus is a person of joy.
The fruit of the Spirit in Galatians 5.
You guys have maybe memorized this when you were kids.
The fruit of the Spirit is love, melancholy, bitterness, frustration, anger.
No.
The fruit of the Spirit is love followed by joy.
The second fruit of the Spirit is joy.
We can choose to find the goodness of God all around us in the midst of our broken world.
Lastly, I'll remind us from Philippians chapter 4.
Paul says, "Rejoice in the Lord always.
Finally, brothers and sisters, whatever is true, noble, right, pure, lovely, admirable, if anything is excellent or praiseworthy, think about such things."
Get out of the negative feedback loop and get around the table with embodied Christians and share what God is doing all around us.
I just heard a testimony this morning.
And this is why we need community.
This is why we do not neglect to meet around a table and in these spaces with one another.
Can I share it generally?
Absolutely.
Alright.
We had a person who made a blanket, right?
They made a blanket for a patient who was dying of cancer.
And they brought it to our prayer team a few months ago?
Yeah.
About a month and a half.
About a month and a half ago.
And our prayer team prayed over this blanket and prayed for healing and prayed for the kingdom of God to be breaking into the world through this act of sacrificial love.
And the person came back today and said that as far as we can tell, the cancer is gone.
And we hear stories like that.
And the person who had the story immediately picked up his phone and called his friend who helped him pray for the blanket who isn't here and says, "Are you going to church this morning?"
And the guy's like, "Yeah."
And he's like, "Well, I got something for you to praise Jesus about this morning."
We need to fix our eyes on what is praiseworthy and excellent and good.
We need to remind ourselves that even in the brokenness of this world, with the sorrow and pain of sin-marred creation, that God is doing something.
Amen.
That his kingdom is coming and that his will will be done on earth as it is in heaven.
The example of Christ isn't to form a Christian community that is shallow or ignores the realities of a broken world, but it chooses to celebrate where God is at work.
As followers of Christ, we should be full of joy, shining a light of hope to a dark world.
We need each other to do this because again, 85% negative, 95% repetitive.
We need each other to get out of this cycle.
We need to share testimonies of what God has done in our life.
We need to point out the ways in which we see God is at work in others.
And this is not easy.
Many of us have never been, this has never been modeled for us, right?
Many of us have only ever existed in Christian communities where it was shallow, where we talked about whatever everybody else was talking about, the weather and whatever else.
And so if you've never, if it's never been modeled to you, this will feel awkward getting real with people.
I've been working towards this with a small community of people and it gets weird.
A dude kissed me on the neck not too long ago, right?
And I'm like, I don't know how I feel about this.
It gets real.
It gets weird.
But it's beautiful.
It's family around the table.
So it's never been modeled for us.
Life is hectic.
Sometimes, sometimes we're moving so fast that we don't even know how we feel.
Rightness.
And so then the thought of being able to share with somebody else what we feel is really difficult.
This is why these spiritual practices build off of each other, right?
Because if you're practicing solitude on a somewhat regular basis or Sabbath, where you're breaking away from the business of the world and the noise of life, then you're able to, when you come to the table, you're able to bring more of yourself because you're in touch with yourself and with God.
You can be present to yourself and to God.
Some things build off one another.
Some of you can't struggle with this idea because vulnerability has been taken advantage in the past.
You've shared your joys and your sorrows.
And that person that you've shared it with has used and abused or manipulated that information.
And so I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm sympathetic to that.
And I, I realized that for many of us, this will take a long time.
It'll be a slow process.
But I think the alternative is far more painful.
Being alone and isolated and keeping ourselves walled off to the community around us is, is worse than, than not.
All right.
Jesus isn't just a celebrator of God's goodness on earth as it is in heaven, but he is also a mourner of the way that sin has broken good creation.
Going further down in Mark chapter 14, starting at verse 32.
After they celebrated this meal of defiant joy in the midst of one of the hardest situations in human history, Jesus goes to a place called Gethsemane.
And he said to his disciples, Sit here while I pray.
He took Peter, James and John along with them.
And he began to be deeply distressed and troubled.
My soul is overwhelmed with sorrow to the point of death.
He said them, Stay here and keep watch.
Going a little further, he fell on the ground and he prayed, if possible, the hour, that if possible, the hour might pass for him.
Abba, Father, he said, everything is possible for you.
Take this cup from me.
Yet not what I will, but what you will.
This is the same night, right?
They move from this table of celebrating God's deliverance from Egypt's slavery in the past of the Passover lamb.
And they move towards this place of somber prayer, mourning the brokenness.
He's fully aware that the result of sin and death is that he's going to have to face the result of sin and death face to face within the next 24 hours.
And so he invites his disciples to join him in prayer rooted in his suffering.
And he invites his closest followers even further into the suffering and pain.
Joy is something that we could probably celebrate with all of our community.
But sorrow is often reserved for those even closest to us.
Jesus invites his closest three into a vulnerable, deep place of pain reserved for his closest community.
This is why I'm preaching on this for four weeks.
Because you have to do the work to develop the close-knit community before suffering happens.
Because suffering hits and we look around for the people that we're going to go to war with in the prayer closet.
And they're not here because we let the busyness of life keep us from investing in the thing that we've been invited to invest in this whole time.
And then we say things like nobody knows us and we're alone.
And the reality is we have to invest in these relationships when things are fine, when things are normal.
So that when things are hard, they are here for us.
When we're in the regular rhythms of life, it can be so easy to neglect spiritual community.
But if we neglect building it when things are good, we won't have it when things...
I wrote this in my notes.
Fit hits the shan.
Yeah?
Okay.
And as a pastor, I can tell you from experience, from counseling sessions with people,
that Satan does some of his best work when he can get us alone and suffering.
When we can be experiencing sorrow and isolated from the community.
And so we have to, as we go through suffering, and it's hard.
It's hard to be vulnerable.
It's hard to be transparent.
It's hard to acknowledge pain.
We'd rather just create a fake social media post that makes it look like we're going to make it through.
We need to be in community with one another.
Hebrews 3 says it this way:
"See to it, brothers and sisters, that none of you has a sinful, unbelieving heart that turns away from the living God.
But encourage one another daily, as long as it is called today, so that none of you will be hardened by sin's deceitfulness."
I often think about this as like sin, like temptation.
But I think it's also the sorrows, the brokenness of the life that we live on earth.
And sorrow has a way of hardening our hearts towards God's goodness.
And so it says, "Meet with one another daily, encourage one another, so that when sorrow comes, when pain comes,
you can remind each other that this isn't the end of the story.
We need spiritual community that becomes like family, so that when sorrow comes, we don't become overcome by it.
Believing the lies from the enemy that harden our heart to the redemptive work that God is doing."
This spiritual truth is backed up by modern science.
In his teaching on this that some of you will watch in your small groups this week,
John Mark Homer quotes a study done on people who went through significant traumatic events.
And the scientists were trying to figure out that all of us have seen people that went through traumatic events
and some people come out on the other end stronger, better, like more whole as a human being,
and other people like let it destroy their lives and crash the plane and burn out, right?
And so they were doing this study on these people who had significant trauma in their lives,
and they were trying to figure out what is the difference?
What is the thing that makes some people come out of it stronger, some people learn and grow,
and other people crash the plane.
They had their theories, they had their hypothesis, which turned out to be wrong,
and what they came up with is that for those people that had a relational home for their pain,
they were the ones who were most likely to come out of traumatic events on the other end stronger and better for it.
This is biblical truth expressed in science.
We need one another to carry the burdens of this broken world.
I love how Comer summarizes this section in his teaching.
He says, "If Jesus needs a few friends to bear the weight of the cross,
how much more do we need each other to bear our crosses?"
Jesus, fully human and fully God, weeping in the garden,
with Peter, James, and John, supposed to be weeping with him instead falling asleep.
We might have time to get to that, I'm not sure.
If Jesus needs people, how much more do we?
And if you're anything like me, you probably like the idea of this message.
But the execution is hard.
And I think most of us are a lot like the disciples.
The spirit is willing, but the flesh is weak.
As you lean into community, as you seek to go past spiritual platitudes and small talk,
it will be difficult and the enemy will whisper a thousand excuses in your ear for why you shouldn't get vulnerable,
for why you shouldn't be transparent, for why you shouldn't share what's going on in your life,
for why you shouldn't point out to somebody else what you see God doing in their life.
There will be a million excuses and it will be far easier just to say,
"Weather looks good out there for the next week, doesn't it?
How's your fantasy football team doing?"
Right?
It will always be easier to do that.
Spirit is willing, but the flesh is weak.
As I was writing that section of my message, I reminded, I told you,
I've been working on developing a community like this.
It's not easy.
It takes time.
I was reminded of this evening that some of my spiritual community had gotten together
and one of the people in the community suggested that we get vulnerable and transparent,
that we share some things that have been going on,
some things that we've been wrestling with,
some things we've been holding on to.
And the person suggested it and then a week went by and we came together
and it came to that point where it was going to be the time for us to do it.
And the person who had suggested it said,
"I changed my mind.
Let's not do this."
The Spirit is willing.
The flesh is weak.
It's like we want to do it, but, oh man, it's going to be so hard.
And we all, we pushed through it and we all took turns and we all shared.
And the person whose idea it was kept,
"Nah, I'll go last, I'll go last, I'll go last."
And then there was no more people to go.
It was their turn.
And they were like, "Hmm, maybe next week."
And I watched this person.
I watched him overcome all of the lies of the enemy that said,
"Don't get vulnerable with these people.
Don't share with them what you're going through.
Don't share with them this thing that you've been carrying."
Shame, fear, lies from the enemy.
And I watched this person by the power of the Spirit,
through the trembling of their lips,
get out this thing that they've been holding on to.
And I just watched freedom break through.
Grace be extended.
We need each other to carry our burdens.
We need each other in the joy and in the sorrow.
So the application for this week is real easy.
It's just a little bit from last week added on to.
Get around the table with some brothers and sisters in Christ.
Share a meal together.
And don't settle for small talk or spiritual platitudes.
Share a joy and a sorrow.
Share a high and a low from the weak.
Encourage one another and pray for one another.
This is small little baby steps that over time will have compounding interest.
I stole the wording of this from a pastor.
I loved how he said it.
He said, "Trade shallow for honest."
And he quoted his worship pastor.
John Mark Homer talks about highs and lows in his teaching.
Share a high and a low from the weak.
The worship pastor at this guy's church had one that was even better.
I love this.
Share a nope, a dope, and a hope.
Like this past week, what was like nope?
What was dope?
And what do we have hope for in the coming week?
Trade shallow for honest and trade comparison for compassion.
We're going to be tempted when somebody that's in our community brings something that they want to celebrate to us.
The flesh in us is going to be tempted to compare their joy with our joy.
To covet, to do all kinds of nasty, sinful stuff.
Stop comparing your story to their story and just be present with them.
Celebrate what God's doing in their life and sit with them in the sorrows and brokenness of this world.
All right, as we land the plane here, I want to make sure that we see the main thing that connects both Christ's joy and his sorrow in these passages.
Because I think it's important.
I think it's important that we remind ourselves why we're putting an emphasis on Christian community.
We should absolutely love and invest in relationships with people outside the faith.
We should love our neighbors.
We should invest in our coworkers.
But the reason that we prioritize Christian community is because we, as followers of Jesus, interpret the circumstances of this broken world the same way.
We need to remind ourselves of what's actually happening, of the spiritual realities behind the physical realities.
And that's what we see in this passage.
I'm going to read both and just see if you find one particular thing that is present.
While they were eating, Jesus took bread and when he had given thanks, he broke it and he gave it to his disciples saying, "Take, this is my body."
I'm going to give you guys a hint because it might be harder than I thought it was going to be.
Okay?
Just pay attention.
Then he took a cup and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them and they all drank from it.
The center of Christ's joy.
Later, going a little farther, he fell to the ground and he prayed, "If possible this hour might pass from him, Abba, Father."
He said, "Everything is possible for you.
Take this cup from me.
Yet not what I will, but what you will."
Both at the center of Christ's joy and his suffering is a cup.
They're different cups.
There's spiritual realities behind the physical realities.
The suffering that Jesus is about to experience is a result of all of humanity's rebellion towards God.
It is the cup of God's wrath that Jesus will receive on our behalf.
And as followers of Jesus, we realize that all suffering, every suffering that we experience on earth is somehow a result of sin.
It's either our sin, others' sin, or the unintended consequences of a broken world.
And so when we come in contact with sorrow as Christians, we remind ourselves that this is not God's will for our lives.
That this is, in some way, the brokenness of this world being played out.
So we encourage one another daily, not to be hardened by the lies of sin, but to put our hope in Christ, whose heel was bruised, but who crushed the head of the serpent through his resurrection.
All sorrow and suffering is but a vapor compared to the eternal glory we are awaiting in Christ Jesus.
Not only is there a cup at the center of Christ's suffering, but there is a cup at the center of his joy.
And that is the cup of God's blessing, his grace.
Just like followers of Jesus know that all suffering is rooted in sin.
We know that all joy that we experience is rooted in God's grace.
That's all a gift.
And this is why we have to remind ourselves.
We have to come around Christian community because it's a very big temptation for us to get that raise at work and say, "Man, did I work hard for that."
It's a gift.
The breath in your lungs is a gift.
Every joy that we experience on earth is a gift from God that we did not earn and we do not deserve, and yet he freely gives it to us.
James 1, "Every good and perfect gift is from above, coming down from the Father of the heavenly lights, who does not change like shifting shadows."
He chose to give us birth through the word of truth that we might be a kind of first fruits of all that he created.
Eventually, all creation will catch up to this reality that every good and perfect thing is a gift from God.
But right now, we are the first fruits of that reality.
So we root our joy in the reality that it is a gift from God.
Poor David.
I don't think David sang yet at church.
And of course, I asked him to sing a solo by himself at the end of the service.
So be gracious, right?
Love on David.
I want to conclude today's message with a new song that I think handles this tension well.
Worship songs are all about joy, right?
We love to sing happy songs.
And sometimes we sing sad songs, but rarely are there songs that carry the tension of both.
And I listened to the song recently and I love it because the one verse says, "If your life's been resurrected by the war that Jesus won, praise the Lord."
And the next verse says, "For the one who's brokenhearted and it's hard to sing this song."
And that is what Christian community is all about.
There are people in this room who have stories and testimonies of God's resurrection power this morning.
We got people like Joe coming in here and saying, "Let me tell you a story about a girl who thought she had no worth."
And how Jesus resurrected those dry bones and made life again.
We've got those stories in here.
And we also have stories of loss of job, of miscarriage, of diagnosis, of whatever it might be.
There are joy and sorrow in here and we need to remind ourselves that the sorrow is temporary and won't last forever.
We need to remind ourselves that joy is a gift from God.
May we be a church that intentionally forms Christian family around a table that isn't shallow or built on spiritual platitudes,
but that fights to defiantly celebrate joy and intentionally carry one another's sufferings.
"Praise the Lord, praise the Lord, praise the Lord, praise the Lord forever.
Let His name, let all within me sing.
Praise the Lord forever.
Praise the Lord."
If your life can resurrect
By the war that Jesus won
If you wait in expectation
For a kingdom yet to come
All you citizens of heaven
And daughters of the King
Come on to church
Lift your voice and sing
Praise the Lord
Praise the Lord forever
That's His name
Let all within me sing
Praise the Lord forever
Oh, the one who's brokenhearted
And it's hard to sing this song
You've been walking through the valleys
And your faith is feeling small
I pray peace and love surround you
From the God who understands
As the family all around you
Lift your arms up when you can
Join the choir of creation
With the song of the redeemed
Come on, church
Lift your voice and sing
Praise the Lord
Praise the Lord forever
Forever
Let His name
Let all within me sing
Praise the Lord
Love to invite you to stand
And read these words of Scripture
Over us as a prayer
Romans chapter 12
Father, may this passage
Become a reality in our community
As we slowly but surely
Invest in the joys and sorrows
Of those around us
Love must be sincere
Hate what is evil
And cling to what is good
Be devoted to one another in love
Honor one another above yourselves
Never be lacking in zeal
But keep your spiritual fervor
Serving the Lord
Be joyful in hope
Patient in affliction
Faithful in prayer
Share with the Lord's people
Who are in need
Who practice hospitality
Bless those who persecute you
Bless and do not curse
Rejoice with those who rejoice
Mourn with those who mourn
Live in harmony with love
Do not be proud
But be willing to associate
With people in low position
Do not be conceited
Do not obey evil for evil
Be careful to do what is right
In the eyes of everyone
If impossible
As far as it depends on you
Let it be with everyone
Do not take revenge
My dear friends
But leave room for God's wrath
From his sin
If he is mine to avenge
I will return to the Lord
On the contrary
And then he is hungry to feed him
If he is thirsty
And he has something to take
In doing this
He will keep our evil goals on set
Do not overcome evil
But overcome evil with good
Go in peace church
And visit the prayer table
If you have needs
Thank you for your time to come to the Lord's office